We’re excited to announce our latest improvements for B2B companies including a new Hubspot Integration and a wide variety of APIs. [Learn more here.](https://fastspring.com/blog/fastspring-launches-hubspot-integration-and-expands-its-b2b-offering-with-summer-product-releases/)

Product

* [
    
    **Global Payments**  
    Easily transact across borders](https://fastspring.com/global-payments/)
* [
    
    **Fraud Prevention**  
    Intelligent alerts, fewer chargebacks](https://fastspring.com/risk-management-and-compliance/)
* [
    
    **Subscription Management**  
    Flexible recurring billing tools](https://fastspring.com/subscription-management/)
* [
    
    **Affiliate Marketing**  
    Find engaged buyers for your product](https://fastspring.com/affiliates/)
* [
    
    **Checkout**  
    Localized, Embedded, and Branded](https://fastspring.com/branded-checkout/)
* [
    
    **Digital Invoicing**  
    Pain-free B2B digital sales](https://fastspring.com/digital-invoicing/)
* [
    
    **Tax Compliance**  
    We handle all taxes including VAT](https://fastspring.com/tax-management/)
* [
    
    **Interactive Quotes**  
    Streamline custom SaaS deals](https://fastspring.com/interactive-quotes/)
* [
    
    **Reporting and Analytics**  
    Understand Everything about Subscriptions and Revenue](https://fastspring.com/reporting/)
* [
    
    **Merchant of Record**  
    We handle the complexities of global selling for you](https://fastspring.com/merchant-of-record/)
* [
    
    **Developer Tools**  
    Review the most recent resources for building your store experience](https://fastspring.com/fastspring-developer-tools/)

  Use Cases

* [**Downloadable Software** Save time while increasing conversions](https://fastspring.com/solutions/selling-software-online/)
* [**eLearning and Courses** Easily sell courses on your own site](https://fastspring.com/solutions/elearning/)

  Developers

Resources

[![[Customer Story] Why TestDome Considers FastSpring a Real Partner](https://fastspring.com/wp-content/themes/fastspring-bamboo/images/promotional/2023/FastSpring-TestDome-blog-thumbnail.jpg)

#### \[Customer Story\] Why TestDome Considers FastSpring a Real Partner

TestDome has loved FastSpring's product and support for a long time.

FIND OUT WHY →](https://fastspring.com/blog/testdome-considers-fastspring-a-real-partner-for-selling-software-online/)

[

Sell SaaS, software, and digital goods

Sign In](https://app.fastspring.com/)

[

B2B sales quotes to close deals fast

Sign In](https://iq.fastspring.com/)[Question a Charge](https://fastspring.com/consumer-support/)

Loading search...

Show results from: [fastspring.com](#) [Docs](#)

#### Results from fastspring.com

Get more than a payment gateway, right out of the gate. Go farther faster with FastSpring.
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

[Schedule Demo](https://fastspring.com/request-demo/) or [Try Now](https://fastspring.com/sign-up/)

FastSpring® Privacy Statement
-----------------------------

**_Please note:_** _This is the FastSpring Privacy Policy. There is also a separate privacy policy for FastSpring Interactive Quotes (formerly SalesRight) which_ [_you can access here_](https://iq.fastspring.com/privacy)_._

California residents and individuals located in the European Economic Area (EEA), the United Kingdom (UK) and Switzerland can exercise their privacy rights, including the right to request access to or deletion of their personal information, subject to the exceptions under applicable law, by clicking [**here**](https://fastspring.com/privacy/data-request/) and then completing the form to submit their request.

You may find a copy of this Privacy Policy in PDF format [**here**](https://fastspring.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/fastspring-privacy-policy-june-2020.pdf).  For individuals with disabilities, alternative methods of viewing or receiving this Privacy Policy can be found [**here**](https://fastspring.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/fastspring-privacy-policy-june-2020.pdf).

BY USING THIS WEBSITE OR ANY FASTSPRING OPERATED ECOMMERCE SOLUTION OR SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO FASTSPRING THROUGH THIS WEBSITE OR ANY FASTSPRING POWERED ECOMMERCE SOLUTION, YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE COLLECTION, USE, TRANSFER, AND DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION AS DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO ABIDE BY THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT, DO NOT USE THIS WEBSITE. YOUR CONTINUED USE OF THE WEBSITE FOLLOWING THE POSTING OF ANY CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT CONSTITUTES ACCEPTANCE OF SUCH CHANGES.

**1\. Scope and Purpose of This Privacy Statement.**

_Introduction._ This Bright Market, LLC d/b/a FastSpring (“**FastSpring**”, “**we**”, “**our**” or “**us**”) Privacy Statement (“**Privacy Statement**”) applies to each ecommerce solution, which may be but is not limited to, a website, portion of a website or a software application branded with the look and feel of a software publisher or entity operated by FastSpring for the purpose of buying or selling such software publisher’s products and/or services (“**Ecommerce Engine**” or “**Website**”) where this Privacy Statement can be accessed from a hyperlink on, or otherwise appears on, that Ecommerce Engine.  If you are purchasing products through a software Seller (“**Vendor**”), a FastSpring subsidiary and not FastSpring directly, please note that this Ecommerce Engine is hosted and/or operated by FastSpring under an agreement with the Vendor or subsidiary of FastSpring who is listed as the seller of products in the terms of sale on this Ecommerce Engine.

_Controller Responsible for Your Information._ Depending upon your relationship to us, FastSpring operates as either a joint controller or processor of the Personal Information we maintain about you.  For additional information on the distinction between the two roles, please see our [Data Processing Agreement](https://fastspring.com/terms-use/data-processing-agreement/).  Any Personal Information collected by visiting this Website is controlled by Bright Market, LLC d/b/a FastSpring, 801 Garden Street, #201, Santa Barbara, CA 93101, United States of America.

_Purpose._  FastSpring respects the privacy of its customers, partners and suppliers of products or services. The purpose of this Privacy Statement is to provide you with information concerning how FastSpring collects, uses, maintains, and shares your Personal Information in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

**2\. Information We Collect and Process.**

FastSpring collects the Personal Information of our purchasers, Vendors, and other individuals who visit our Website for specified, explicit purposes only and will not process this Personal Information in a manner that is incompatible with those purposes.  Personal Information will be processed only if such processing is based on any of the legal grounds listed in section 6(1) of the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR) (unless an exemption applies) as outlined below:

* _Performance of a Contract with You_. We will process your Personal Information if it is necessary in order to enter into or perform a contract with you. For example, we will process your payment information in order to complete your purchase/sales transaction.
* _Legitimate Interest_.  We will process your Personal Information if it is necessary for the purposes of FastSpring’s legitimate interests, except where FastSpring’s interests are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms that require protection of your Personal Information. FastSpring’s legitimate interests in processing your Personal Information include:  FastSpring’s prevention of fraud or misuse of services, IT and network security, marketing and advertising of products sold by FastSpring, enforcement of legal claims including debt collection via out-of-court procedures, processing for marketing research purposes.
* _Consent_. If you are located in the EEA, UK, or Switzerland, by using this Ecommerce Engine you consent by ticking the specific consent box to the processing of your Personal Information FastSpring’s servers in the United States and the storage of your Personal Information in the United States for the purposes set forth in this Privacy Statement, and acknowledge that your Personal Information may be transmitted by us to other FastSpring companies for the purposes set out in this Privacy Statement and for company group administration purposes. You may withdraw your consent at any time with effect for the future, but you will then not be able to use our services and in particular order products on our Websites. Where consent to the collection of Personal Information is revoked, we will stop processing that Personal Information. For further information or if you wish to withdraw your consent, please email us at [privacy@fastspring.com](mailto:privacy@fastspring.com).
* _Legal Obligation_. We will process your Personal Information where we are under a legal obligation to do so, including tax compliance obligations.

When you visit, buy, or sell via our Website, we may capture the following information about you:

| **Categories of Personal Information Collected** | **Specific Personal Information** | **Source of Personal Information** | **Purpose of Collection** | **Legal Grounds for Collection** |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Identifiers | Name (First/Last), Signature/E-Signature, Mailing Address, Email Address, Telephone Number(s), IP Address, Driver’s License Number/Other Government Number (GST/VAT), Tax Exemption Status, Bank Account Numbers, Debit/Credit Card Number & Information, Customer Identification. | Purchase/Sale Information, Account/Mailing List Registration, Cookie, Web Beacon, Other Technologies, Transaction Details You Provide to Our Customer Service Teams, Information We Receive from Vendors. | Complete Purchase/Sales Transactions, Customer Service Issues, Marketing, Legal and Regulatory Obligations | Consent, Necessary for Performance of Contract, Compliance with Legal Obligation, Legitimate Interest. |
| Internet or Other Similar Network Activity | Browsing History, Search History, Other Information Related to Our Consumer’s Interactions with Our Website, Application, and/or Advertisements, including (1) Buyer Usage Activities (adding/removing products from checkout; currency used for purchase) and Analytics, (2) Vendor Platform Usage Activities (submissions, clicks on navigation links, video usage and duration, page views, search requests, time spent on page, cursor movement, clicks on any “get support” or “sign up” buttons) and Analytics. | Purchase/Sale Information, Cookie, Web Beacon, Other Technologies, Third Party Sources. | Complete Purchase/Sale Transactions, Marketing, Understand Our Customers, Improve Our Products/Usage and Data Analytics. | Consent, Necessary for Performance of Contract, Compliance with Legal Obligation, Legitimate Interest. |
| Commercial Information | Records of Products or Services Purchased, Obtained, or Considered. | Purchase/Sale Information. | Complete Purchase/Sale Transactions. | Consent, Necessary for Performance of Contract, Compliance with Legal Obligation, Legitimate Interest. |
| Geolocation Data | Location of the Individual and Device Used to Access Our Website. | Purchase/Sale Information, Account/Mailing List Registration, Cookie, Web Beacon, Other Technologies. | Complete Purchase/Sale Transactions, Marketing, Legal and Regulatory Obligations. | Consent, Necessary for Performance of Contract, Compliance with Legal Obligation, Legitimate Interest. |

_Marketing Communications_.  We may send you email marketing communication about FastSpring products and services, invite you to participate in our events or surveys, or otherwise communicate with you for marketing purposes, provided that we do so in accordance with the consent requirements that are imposed by applicable law. You may opt out of receiving marketing communication at any time.

_Our Use of Anonymous Information._  We may use anonymous information (i.e. information that does not allow direct or indirect identification of the individual to whom such information relates) collected by us:

* to personalize and support your use of this Ecommerce Engine, our services, and/or the services of our partners;
* to improve this Ecommerce Engine, the customer experience, our advertising systems, and our products and services;
* for fraud prevention purposes, such as device fingerprinting;
* to identify actions or transactions as originating through an affiliate marketing or referral program;
* to deliver targeted advertisements on this Ecommerce Engine and other Websites and/or ecommerce solutions;
* to provide reporting to our current and prospective partners and service providers; and
* for statistical or research and analysis purposes.

In addition, we may anonymize Personal Information by removing any information that identifies you specifically, and use the rest for the purposes set forth above.

**3\. Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies.**

A cookie is a commonly used automated data collection tool. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer or device by websites that you visit or HTML-formatted emails you open, in order to make websites work, or to work more efficiently. We may use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags or other similar technologies on our Websites or emails to, among other things:

* Tailor information presented to you based on your browsing preferences, such as language and geographical region;
* Collect statistics regarding your Website usage;
* Provide us with information to support technical functionality of service, improve the Website experience and measure marketing effectiveness; and
* In some cases, to enable a third party to deliver future advertising for our products and services to you when you visit certain Websites owned by such third parties.

There are several different kinds of cookies, and should we be deploying cookies we (or a third party provider be deploying them in connection with our ecommerce activities) would be using one of the following common types of cookies, which may be persistent cookies or session cookies:

* **_Essential cookies_** are necessary to provide you with services and features available through our Websites. Without these cookies, services you may need, such as shopping carts or e-billing, cannot be provided.
* **_Analytics or customization cookies_** collect information that is either used in aggregate form to help us understand how the Website is being used or how effective our marketing campaigns are, or to help us customize the Website for you.
* **_Advertising cookies and tracking scripts_** are used to make advertising messages more relevant to you. They perform functions like preventing the same ad from continuously reappearing, ensuring that ads are properly delivered and, in some cases, featuring ads based on your interests.

If the Website includes a cookie management tool, you will typically find a hover button at the bottom of your screen. If in the future you do not wish to receive cookies, you may be able to refuse them by adjusting your browser settings to reject cookies. If you do so, we may be unable to offer you some of our functionalities, services or support. If you have previously visited our Websites, you may also have to delete any existing cookies from your browser.

_Do-Not-Track._  There are different ways you can prevent tracking of your online activity. One of them is setting a preference in your browser that alerts websites you visit that you do not want them to collect certain information about you. This is referred to as a Do-Not-Track (“DNT”) signal. Please note that our Websites may not recognize or take action in response to DNT signals from web browsers. At this time, there is no universally accepted standard for what a company should do when a DNT signal is detected. In the event a final standard is established, we will assess how to appropriately respond to these signals. For more detailed information about cookies, Do-Not-Track and other tracking technologies, please visit [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

_Third Party Data Collection._  This may also include cookies placed by third parties, to deliver tailored information and content which may be of interest to you, such as promotions or offerings, when you visit third party websites after you have left our Websites. We do not permit these third parties to collect Personal Information about you (such as email address) on our Website, nor do we share with them any Personal Information about you.

_Social Media Features and Widgets_.  Our Websites may include social media features, such as Facebook’s “Like” button, and widgets, such as the “Share This” button. These features are usually recognizable by their third-party brand or logo and may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Website, and set a cookie to enable the feature to work properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Website. **Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.** Currently, we use the features and widgets (“**Plugins**”) of Facebook, Google, Twitter, and LinkedIn offered by the companies Facebook Inc., Google Inc., Twitter Inc. and LinkedIn Corporation (“**Providers**”).

* Facebook is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“**Facebook**”). You will find an overview on Facebook’s Plugins and what they look like here: [https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins)
* Google+ is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“**Google**”). You will find an overview on Google’s Plugins and what they look like here: [https://developers.google.com/+/web/](https://developers.google.com/+/web/)
* Twitter is operated by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA (“**Twitter**”). You will find an overview on Twitter’s Plugins and what they look like here: [https://twitter.com/about/resources/buttons](https://twitter.com/about/resources/buttons)
* LinkedIn is operated by LinkedIn Corporation, 1000 West Maude Avenue, Sunnyvale CA 94085, USA (“**LinkedIn**”). You will find an overview on LinkedIn’s Plugin and what they look like here: [https://developer.linkedin.com/plugins](https://developer.linkedin.com/plugins)

When you access one of our Websites, which contains a Plugin, your browser establishes a direct connection with the servers of Facebook, Google, Twitter, and LinkedIn. The content of the Plugin is transferred by the respective Provider directly to your browser, which then integrates it into the Website. Integration of the Plugin allows the Provider to receive the information that you have accessed the respective Website even if you do not maintain a profile with that Provider or if you are not logged in at the moment. This information (including your IP address) will be transferred by your browser directly to the Provider in the U.S. and stored there. If you are logged in with one of the Providers’ services, they will be able to assign your visit on our Website to your profile with the respective Provider. If you interact with any of the Plugins, e.g. by pressing the ‟Like” or the ‟+1” button, this information will also be sent directly to the server of the Provider and stored there. The information will also be published in the social network on your respective account, e.g. Twitter, and displayed to your contacts there.

For more information on the purpose and extent of the data acquisition and how data are processed and used by the respective Provider as well as regarding your rights and optional settings to protect your privacy, please refer to the privacy policies of the respective Provider:

* Privacy Policy of Facebook: [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy)
* Privacy Policy of Google: [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy)
* Privacy Policy of Twitter: [https://twitter.com/en/privacy](https://twitter.com/en/privacy)
* Privacy Policy of LinkedIn: [https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)

If you do not want Google, Facebook, Twitter or LinkedIn to allocate data collected on our Websites to your profile in their service, you must log out of the respective service before visiting our Website. You can prevent the loading of the Plugins completely by using Add-Ons for your browser, e.g. the script-blocker ‟NoScript” ([http://noscript.net/](http://noscript.net/)).

If you accept a session or persistent cookie, you can delete it at any time through your web browser (e.g., as soon as you leave our Ecommerce Engine).  If you do not wish to receive cookies or wish to manage when you accept cookies in general, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer. Although you are not required to accept our cookies, if you set your browser to reject cookies, you may not be able to use all of the features and functionality of this Ecommerce Engine.

We and our partners use third party service providers in connection with this Ecommerce Engine and our business to gather user metrics and usage data. These service providers may collect anonymous information about your visits to our Ecommerce Engine or to a Website, your interaction with our Ecommerce Engine or that Website, and the products and services offered by us, our partners and our suppliers through the use of cookies, pixel tags, JavaScript code or other web technologies. This information may be transferred to servers in the U.S. and stored there. We and our partners may use this anonymous information to provide targeted advertisements to you for goods and services, for marketing analysis, and for quality improvement purposes. Currently, we use the following web tracking services:

* _Google Analytics_: Google Analytics is a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the Website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Website will normally be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. In case of activation of the IP anonymization, Google will shorten the IP address in EU Member States or other countries of the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. On behalf of the Website provider Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Website, compiling reports on Website activity for Website operators and providing other services relating to Website activity and internet usage to the Website provider. Google will not associate the IP address transmitted by your browser with any other data stored by Google.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do so, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this Website. Furthermore, you can prevent the acquisition of data collected by cookies and relating to your use of the Website (including your IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). Please note that on this Website, Google Analytics code is supplemented by “anonymizeIp”. This allows to process IP addresses in a shortened form to exclude direct reference to a specific person. For more information provided by Google: [https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en).

In any case, if you want to manage, deactivate or authorize the cookies, you can use the below links:

* Internet Explorer : [https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)
* Chrome : [https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en)
* Safari : [https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201265](https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201265)
* Mozilla : [https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences)
* Opera : [http://help.opera.com/Windows/10.20/en/cookies.html](http://help.opera.com/Windows/10.20/en/cookies.html)

**4\. Sharing Your Personal Information.**

We may share your Personal Information in a limited number of circumstances, including with:

* _Our Partners._ When we make products available for sale through an Ecommerce Engine, we are doing so as an independent ecommerce reSeller of, or service provider for, the partner whose name and/or logo appears as part of the particular Ecommerce Engine. In connection with your purchase of a product or service through an online store we operate that is co-branded with our partner’s branding, we will provide certain of the Personal Information and/or anonymous information you provide in connection with your purchase to that partner for reporting purposes, to allow our partner or its service provider to register your purchase, to enable your access to products or services provided by our partner or its suppliers, to facilitate warranty, technical support or after-sales service, to allow our partner or its subcontractor to send communications to you if you have previously consented to receive them, to allow our partner or its service provider to provide services in connection with this Ecommerce Engine such as customer support or single sign-on functionality on this Ecommerce Engine and our partner’s Website, or for similar purposes in order to fulfill obligations to you. We may also provide certain of the Personal Information you provide in connection with your purchase to the publisher or manufacturer of a product you purchase, or operator of a service for which you purchase a service use right from us, if different than the partner whose name and/or logo appears on this Ecommerce Engine.  The privacy policy of our partner, and of the publisher, manufacturer or operator of the product or service you purchase, will govern how that party uses and protects any of your Personal Information that we provide to them.
* _Our Service Providers_. We use other companies, which may include but are not limited to present or future corporate affiliates, to provide joint services or certain services to us or on our behalf and help us to operate our business. We may share your information with our service providers in connection with their provision of services to us. We may also allow these companies to use anonymous information, and to use aggregated Personal Information on an anonymous basis (i.e., where the aggregated data cannot identify you personally), for their business purposes.  We will not share your Personal Information with our affiliates or unrelated third parties to use for their own marketing purposes without your consent. We select our partners and service providers on the basis of their security and confidentiality commitments and their compliance with data protection laws.
* _To Comply With Legal Requirements, Cooperate With Law Enforcement, Prevent Fraud and Other Crimes, and Protect Legal Rights, Ecommerce Engine, You and Others_. To the extent not expressly prohibited by applicable law, we may disclose Personal Information we collect on this Ecommerce Engine without notifying you when we, in good faith, believe disclosure is appropriate: (a)  to comply with the law or a regulatory requirement; (b) to comply with governmental, administrative or judicial process, requirement or order, such as a subpoena or court order; (c) to cooperate with law enforcement or other governmental investigations (without necessarily requiring the law enforcement or government agency requesting the information to formally serve us with a subpoena); (d) to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft; (e) to enforce a contract; to protect the legal rights, property or safety of FastSpring, its corporate affiliates, and their respective employees, clients and partners and agents, other users or the public in general; or (f) to protect your vital interests if determined necessary by us. In addition, we may review our server logs for security purposes, such as detecting intrusions into our network. If we suspect criminal activity, we may share our server logs – which contain visitors’ IP addresses – with the appropriate investigative authorities who may use that information to trace and identify individuals. We also reserve the right to report to appropriate law enforcement or government agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe are or may be in violation of applicable laws, rules or regulations without providing notice to you. We are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). We may be required to disclose Personal Information that we handle under the Privacy Shield in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
* _In Connection With Corporate Events/Transitions_. If one of our corporate affiliates or a third party has acquired our business, specific assets or the business of one of our operating divisions through which you have provided information to us, for example, as the result of a sale, merger, reorganization, insolvency, dissolution or liquidation, your Personal Information may become owned by that company in compliance with applicable data protection laws. In that event, the acquiring company’s use of your Personal Information will still be subject to this Privacy Statement, any applicable Supplemental Privacy Notices, and the privacy preferences you have expressed to us.

We do not sell your Personal Information.

**5\. Security of Your Personal Information**

We are committed to keeping your Personal Information secure. We have implemented physical, technical and administrative safeguards reasonably designed to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access and disclosure. When we collect or transmit sensitive information such as a financial account number, we use industry standard methods to protect that information. We encrypt Personal Information whenever possible and otherwise restrict access to Personal Information to those employees and individuals with a need to know that information.  It is important that you understand, however, that no Ecommerce Engine, Website, database or system is completely secure or “hacker proof.” You are also responsible for taking reasonable steps to protect your Personal Information against unauthorized disclosure or misuse, for example, by protecting your password. Different countries have different privacy laws and requirements. Please know, however, that no matter where your Personal Information is collected, used, transferred or stored, if it was collected through this Ecommerce Engine, it will be protected by us in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Statement, any Supplemental Privacy Notices that apply to you, and applicable data protection laws.

_Cross-Border Transfers of Your Data._ As we operate internationally, and provide you with relevant services through our resources and servers around the globe, sharing your Personal Information across borders is essential. Your Personal Information will be processed on the computer servers (currently Amazon Web Services) in the United States of America on which our Ecommerce Engine is hosted.  In some cases, we may transmit your Personal Information to (i) third party data processors or (ii) product manufacturers, licensors and/or suppliers for the purposes set forth in this Privacy Statement. To the extent required by applicable data protection laws, we have executed standard contractual clauses to effect the lawful cross-border transfer of personal information.

_EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (EU-U.S. DPF) Compliance._  FastSpring complies with the EU-U.S. DPF as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce. FastSpring has certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce that it adheres to the EU-U.S. DPF program Principles (EU-U.S. DPF Principles) with regard to the processing of personal data received from the European Union in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the EU-U.S. DPF Principles, the Principles shall govern. To learn more about the DPF program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/).

* In compliance with the EU-U.S. DPF Principles, FastSpring commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your Personal Information transferred to the United States pursuant to the DPF Principles. European Union individuals with DPF inquiries or complaints should first contact FastSpring at [privacy@fastspring.com](mailto:privacy@fastspring.com).
* FastSpring has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the DPF Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, Data Privacy Framework Services, operated by BBB National Programs. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [https://bbbprograms.org/programs/all-programs/dpf-consumers/ProcessForConsumers](https://bbbprograms.org/programs/all-programs/dpf-consumers/ProcessForConsumers) for more information and to file a complaint. This service is provided free of charge to you.
* If your DPF complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms. See [https://dataprivacyframework.gov/s/article/G-Arbitration-Procedures-dpf?tabset-35584=2](https://dataprivacyframework.gov/s/article/G-Arbitration-Procedures-dpf?tabset-35584=2).

As explained here we sometimes provide Personal Information to third parties to perform services on our behalf. If we transfer Personal Information received under the EU-U.S. DPF to a third party, the third party’s access, use, and disclosure of the Personal Information must also be in compliance with our EU-U.S. DPF obligations. Therefore, third parties that use our products explicitly agree to abide by the EU-U.S. DPF or otherwise agree to execute the Standard Contractual Clauses issued by the European Commission for the purposes of transferring Personal Information from the EU to non-adequate countries outside the EU.

Where the EU-U.S. DPF is not applicable, including when there are transfers from the United Kingdom (UK) or Switzerland, FastSpring executes the Standard Contractual Clauses for the purposes of lawful transfer of personal data as set out in European Commission Decision (EU) 2021/914 of 4 June 2021, as well as the UK International Data Transfer Addendum to the EU Standard Contractual Clauses as issued by the UK Information Commissioner under S119A(1) Data Protection Act 2018 (as applicable to any transfers from the UK to non-adequate third countries).

_Data Retention Policies_.  We will retain your Personal Information only for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which we have collected it. To determine the appropriate retention period, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of your Personal Information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your Personal Information, the purposes for which we process your Personal Information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means and the applicable legal requirements. We will also retain and use your Personal Information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our policies. If you stop using our services or if you delete your account with us, we will delete your information in accordance with applicable laws.

**6\. Your Rights & Choices with Respect to Your Personal Information**

_Your Rights._  Based upon where you reside, certain choices and rights with regards to your Personal Information may be available to you or your authorized agent under applicable data protection laws, such as the GDPR or California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”).

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **  <br>  <br>  <br>**Access Request Rights**** | You have the right to request that we provide to you the following information about our collection and use of your personal information :    <br>1\. The categories of Personal Information we have collected about you.  <br>2\. The categories of sources for the Personal Information we have collected about you (e.g., use of cookies, third party, etc.).  <br>3\. Our business or commercial purpose for collecting that Personal Information.  <br>4\. The categories of third parties with whom we share or have shared that Personal Information.  <br>5\. The specific pieces of Personal Information we collected about you (also called a data portability request), and  <br>6\. Information regarding any disclosures for a business purpose, identifying the Personal Information categories that each category of recipient obtained. |
| ****Deletion, Rectification and Restriction Request Rights**** | You have the right to request that we delete, restrict or, if you believe that our processing of your Personal Information is incorrect or inaccurate, change any of the Personal Information collected from you and retained, subject to certain exceptions.  Once your verifiable consumer request is confirmed, we will delete, restrict or change, as the case may be, and direct our service providers to delete, restrict or change your Personal Information.  Your request to delete the Personal Information collected may be denied if it is necessary for us to retain your information under one or more of the exceptions listed in the GDPR or CCPA. |
| ****Data Portability Rights**** | In some cases, you may receive your Personal Information provided by yourself in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. |
| ****Right to Object**** | Where we process your Personal Information based on a "legitimate interest", you may have the legal right to object to the processing of your Personal Information. |
| ****Right to Revoke Consent**** | Where we process Personal Information based on your consent, you have the right to revoke such consent at any given time. |
| ****Post-mortem Right to Privacy**** | If you are located in EEA, you have the right to set instructions regarding the storage, deletion or communication of your Personal Information after your death. |
| ****Right to Complain**** | You have the legal right to lodge a complaint with the competent authority. |

If you contact us we may, for your protection, ask you for additional information to verify your identity. In most cases, we will provide the access you request, correct or delete any inaccurate Personal Information you discover, cease the processing of your Personal Information and implement your guidelines. We reserve the right, however, to limit or deny your request to the extent permitted by applicable law if the disclosure may lead to a breach of applicable law and regulation, e.g. in case of any legal obligation to retain certain data, or if you have failed to provide sufficient evidence to verify your identity.

_Your Choices._  FastSpring respects your right to make choices about the ways we collect, use and disclose information about you. We generally ask you to indicate your choices at the time, and on the page, where you provide your Personal Information. When you provide Personal Information, we may offer you a choice as to whether you would like to receive further communications from us and/or from our partners via a box to tick for example, such as communications related to updates, upgrades, special offers and pricing. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. If you decide you no longer want to receive promotional messages from us, you may let us know by e-mailing us at [remove@fastspring.com](mailto:remove@fastspring.com) or by following any unsubscribe link in our e-mails; please specify which consent you are revoking in your e-mail to us. Please note, however, if you give us permission to add your contact information to our partner’s mailing list and later withdraw your permission, you will have to contact our partner (or use the “opt-out” provided in the e-mails our partner sends you) to have your name removed from our partner’s mailing lists.

**7\. Links to Third Party Websites**

FastSpring’s Website provides links to third-party web sites, which are not under the control of FastSpring. FastSpring makes no representations about third-party web sites. When you access a non-FastSpring website, you do so at your own risk. FastSpring is not responsible for the reliability of any data, opinions, advice, or statements made on third-party sites. FastSpring provides these links merely as a convenience. The inclusion of such links does not imply that FastSpring endorses, recommends, or accepts any responsibility for the content of such sites.

**8\. Children’s Privacy**

This Ecommerce Engine and our services are not directed at nor targeted to children under the age of 13. If you have not reached the age of majority or are not able to enter into legally binding agreements in your country, you may not use this Ecommerce Engine unless supervised by an adult.  Our goal is to comply with applicable laws and regulations relating to collection and use of information from children as such term is defined by applicable laws. If you believe that we have received information from a child or other person protected under such laws, please notify us immediately by postal mail addressed to FastSpring’s Privacy Department, 801 Garden Street #201, Santa Barbara, CA 93101, United States of America or by e-mail at [privacy@fastspring.com](mailto:privacy@fastspring.com), and we will take reasonable steps to remove that information from our databases.

**9\. Changes to This Privacy Statement**

We may occasionally update this Privacy Statement.  These updates may reflect, among other things, changes in applicable laws, rules or regulations, changes in our data collection practices, and/or changes to our business or services.  If revisions to the Privacy Statement materially affect how we may use Personal Information collected from you prior to the date of the revised statement, then we will request that you opt-in to the revised Privacy Statement via a checkbox for each new order/purchase. We will post an updated version of this Privacy Statement on the Ecommerce Engine with a revised effective date, to let you know that we updated the Privacy Statement.

**10\. How to Contact Us.**

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns regarding this Privacy Statement or our privacy practices, have privacy-related questions not answered online, or if you would like to exercise any of your rights outlined in this Privacy Statement you may contact us by any of the following means:

* _Online Requests:_  You may contact us via our online form located [**here**](https://fastspring.com/privacy/data-request/).
* _By Mail:_ You may contact us by postal mail addressed to Bright Market, LLC d/b/a FastSpring, ATTN: Privacy Department, 801 Garden Street, #201, Santa Barbara, CA 93101, United States of America.
* _By Email:_ You may contact us by e-mail at [privacy@fastspring.com](mailto:privacy@fastspring.com).  Please specify “Global Privacy Question” in the subject line to help us to expedite our review of your e-mail.

You may write to us in your own language.

Products

Solutions

Company

Help

Copyright © 2006-2024 Bright Market, LLC dba FastSpring. 801 Garden St. #201, Santa Barbara, CA 93101 Bright Market LLC dba FastSpring Limited. 2 Minton Place, Victoria Road, Bicester, England, OX26 6QB FastSpring B.V. Fred. Roeskestraat 115, 1076 EE Amsterdam, Netherlands SalesRight Technologies ULC d.b.a FastSpring, 5475 Spring Garden Road, Suite 600 Halifax, NS, B3J 3T2, Canada  
All rights reserved. [Privacy](https://fastspring.com/privacy/) | [Terms](https://fastspring.com/legal/) | [Ethics](https://fastspring.com/ethics/)

Loading video...
